Philip K. Crowe Papers MS109
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1953 -- 1975; 1950 -- 1975; MS109.001; 32.4 Linear Feet
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1971; MS109.001.026.00018 (Box 26)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1971; MS109.001.026.00019 (Box 26)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1971; MS109.001.026.00020 (Box 26)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1972; MS109.001.027.00001 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1972; MS109.001.027.00002 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1972; MS109.001.027.00003 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1973; MS109.001.027.00004 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1973; MS109.001.027.00005 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1973; MS109.001.027.00006 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1974; MS109.001.027.00007 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1974; MS109.001.027.00008 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1975; MS109.001.027.00009 (Box 27)
  - Chronological Embassy Correspondence, Personal, 1975; MS109.001.027.00010 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: Maryland Letters, MS109.001.027.00011 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: Miscellaneous Letters, MS109.001.027.00012 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: Endorsements, MS109.001.027.00013 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: Senate Foreign Relations Committee, MS109.001.027.00014 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: White House, MS109.001.027.00015 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: Congratulation Letters, MS109.001.027.00016 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: List of Ceylon Backers, MS109.001.027.00017 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: Brownell and Dewey, MS109.001.027.00018 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: History of Campaign, MS109.001.027.00019 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: Republican National Committee, MS109.001.027.00020 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, Ceylon Campaign: State Department Letters, MS109.001.027.00021 (Box 27)
- Writings and Research Notes, 1930 -- 1975; MS109.002; 11.3 Linear Feet
  This series contains diaries, newsletters, mission reports for the World Wildlife Foundation, articles, and manuscripts written over the course of Crowe's career and research notes for a 1968 expedition to Africa. This collection spans the period from 1930 to 1975, and the majority of this information is preserved in bound volumes.
  The mission reports are bound volumes detailing Crowe's six Wildlife Missions on behalf the World Wildlife Foundation from 1963-1968, where he visited the Near East, the Far East, the Middle East, Central and South America, and South Africa. There is also a bound volume containing a report compiled by Crowe on polar bears.
  The bound volumes of newsletters are copies of newsletters written by Crowe to family and friends while living and traveling abroad in Europe, the Middle East, Africa, and Asia. These newsletters complement the bound copies of Crowe's personal diaries spanning from 1930 to 1975.
  The diaries cover his experience as an explorer and hunter of big game in French Indo-China, his military career in war time, and also his terms as ambassador to Ceylon, the Union of South Africa, Norway and Denmark. The diaries were reviewed by the United States Department of State to prevent the release of classified information in the interest of national security or foreign relations. Deletions were made in volumes numbered 6, 8, 13, 14, 16, 17, 28, 31, 33, 34, 36, 38, 39, and 43. Numbers appear on the spine of each volume. Among the diaries is a bound volume of Crowe's personal recollections of serving as the Special Assistant to Secretary of State John Foster Dulles from 1957 to 1959.
  The research notes on his expedition to Africa include maps, pamphlets, notes, books, and magazine articles.
  Crowe's articles include a slim volume of articles written while he was a reporter for the New York Evening Post in 1933, as well as articles focusing hunting and fishing. There are also typed copies of several manuscripts written by Crowe about sporting, wildlife, and his diplomatic service. Several of these manuscripts were published: Empty Ark, World Wildlife: The Last Stand, Out of the Mainstream, and Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon whose manuscript title is The Diplomatic Years 1953-1956.
  This series has no arrangement.
  - Letters: Europe, Middle East, 1952; MS109.002.028.00001 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of twenty-one letters and four articles.
  - Letters from Lanka, 1953 -- 1954; MS109.002.028.00002 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of fifty-five letters.
  - Letters from Lanka, 1955 -- 1956; MS109.002.028.00003 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 56-109.
  - African Letters, 1959; MS109.002.028.00004 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 1-35.
  - African Letters, 1960; MS109.002.028.00005 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 36-71.
  - African Newsletters, 1959 -- 1961; MS109.002.028.00006 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of newsletters, numbers 1-80.
  - Embassy to South Africa, 1962; MS109.002.028.00007 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of a report on South Africa.
  - Game of Near East and Africa, 1963; MS109.002.028.00008 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of 38 letters and a report to the World Wildlife Fund on game conservation in the Near East and Africa. Dedication to the Fletcher School on flyleaf.
  - Game of South America, 1964; MS109.002.028.00009 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of 25 letters. Dedication to the Fletcher School on the flyleaf.
  - Wildlife Mission to Far East, 1965; MS109.002.028.00010 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of 40 letters. Dedication to the Fletcher School on flyleaf.
  - Wildlife Mission to the Middle East, 1966; MS109.002.028.00011 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of 14 letters. Dedication to the Fletcher School on flyleaf.
  - Wildlife Mission to the Middle East, 1966; MS109.002.028.00012 (Box 28)
    Bound volume of 17 letters. Dedication to the Fletcher School on flyleaf.
  - Gun and Camera, 1963; MS109.002.029.00001 (Box 29)
    Bound copy of draft of Gun and Camera.
  - The Empty Ark, 1964; MS109.002.029.00002 (Box 29)
    Bound copy of draft of The Empty Ark published by Scribner in 1967.
  - Wildlife Mission to Central America, 1967; MS109.002.029.00003 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of 33 letters. Dedication to Fletcher School on flyleaf.
  - Wildlife Mission to Southern Africa, 1968; MS109.002.029.00004 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of seven letters. Dedication to the Fletcher School on flyleaf.
  - Letters from Norway, 1969; MS109.002.029.00005 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 1-10. Notation "corrected copy" on flyleaf.
  - Letters from Norway, 1970; MS109.002.029.00006 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 11-33.
  - Letters from Norway, 1971; MS109.002.029.00007 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 34-60.
  - Letters from Norway, 1972; MS109.002.029.00008 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 61-78. Dedication to Fletcher School on flyleaf.
  - Polar Bears, 1970; MS109.002.029.00009 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of collected information on polar bears.
  - Danish Newsletters, 1973 -- 1974; MS109.002.029.00010 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 1-25.
  - Danish Newsletters, 1975; MS109.002.029.00011 (Box 29)
    Bound volume of letters, numbers 26-31.
  - Draft: Out of the Mainstream, MS109.002.030.00001 (Box 30)
  - Draft: Out of the Mainstream, MS109.002.030.00002 (Box 30)
  - Draft: Crisis in Southern Africa, MS109.002.030.00003 (Box 30)
    Pages 1-181 with emendations.
  - Draft: Crisis in Southern Africa, MS109.002.030.00004 (Box 30)
    Pages 182-365, with emendations.
  - Draft: The Empty Ark, MS109.002.030.00005 (Box 30)
    Pages 1-304, with emendations.
  - Draft: The Empty Ark, MS109.002.030.00006 (Box 30)
    Pages 305-518, chapter XXIV, with emendations.
  - Draft: Gun and Camera, MS109.002.030.00007 (Box 30)
    Pages 1-294, with emendations.
  - Draft: Guns and Camera, MS109.002.030.00008 (Box 30)
    Pages 295-601, with emendations.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.030.00009 (Box 30)
    Pages 1-207, with emendations. Published as Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.030.00010 (Box 30)
    Pages 208-434, with emendations. Published as Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.030.00011 (Box 30)
    Pages 435-524, with emendations. Published as Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.030.00012 (Box 30)
    Pages525-699, with emendations. Published as Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon.
  - Draft: Visit to Yugoslavia, MS109.002.030.00013 (Box 30)
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.030.00014 (Box 30)
    Copy two with emendations, pages 1-251. Published as Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.030.00015 (Box 30)
    Copy two with emendations, pages 252-485. Published as Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.030.00016 (Box 30)
    Copy two with emendations, pages 486-673. Published as Diversions of a Diplomat in Ceylon.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.031.00001 (Box 31)
    Copy two with emendations, pages 674-868.
  - Draft: The Diplomatic Years, 1953 -- 1956; MS109.002.031.00002 (Box 31)
    Copy two with emendations, pages 869-937.
  - Draft: World Wildlife: The Last Stand, MS109.002.031.00003 (Box 31)
    Copy one with emendations, pages 1-143
  - Draft: World Wildlife: The Last Stand, MS109.002.031.00004 (Box 31)
    Copy one with emendations, pages 144-283.
  - Draft: World Wildlife: The Last Stand, MS109.002.031.00005 (Box 31)
    Copy one with emendations, pages 284-429.
  - Draft: World Wildlife: The Last Stand, MS109.002.031.00006 (Box 31)
    Copy one with emendations, pages 430-601
  - Ceylon-Indore, MS109.002.031.00007 (Box 31)
    Newsletters
  - Ceylon-Indore, MS109.002.031.00008 (Box 31)
  - Ceylon-Indorre, MS109.002.031.00009 (Box 31)
  - Ceylon-Indore, MS109.002.031.00010 (Box 31)
  - Draft: World WIldlife: The Last Stand, MS109.002.031.00011 (Box 31)
    Copy two with emendations, pages 1-311.
  - Draft: World Wildlife: The Last Stand, MS109.002.031.00012 (Box 31)
    Copy two with emendations, pages 312-601.
  - South American Expedition Notes, Fair, 1962; MS109.002.031.00013 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, 1962; MS109.002.031.00014 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Travel Plans etc., 1962; MS109.002.031.00015 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, South American Letters, 1962; MS109.002.031.00016 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Itinerary, 1962; MS109.002.031.00017 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Newsletters List, 1962; MS109.002.031.00018 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Letters-General, 1962; MS109.002.031.00019 (Box 31)
  - South America Expedition Notes, South America-General, 1962; MS109.002.031.00020 (Box 31)
  - South America Expedition Notes, Argentina, 1962; MS109.002.031.00021 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Bolivia, 1962; MS109.002.031.00022 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Brazil, 1962; MS109.002.031.00023 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, British Guiana, 1962; MS109.002.031.00024 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Chile, 1962; MS109.002.031.00025 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Colombia, 1962; MS109.002.031.00026 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Ecuador, 1962; MS109.002.031.00027 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, French Guiana, 1962; MS109.002.031.00028 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Letters, 1962; MS109.002.031.00029 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, 1962; MS109.002.031.00030 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Paraguay, 1962; MS109.002.031.00031 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Surinam, 1962; MS109.002.031.00032 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Uruguay, 1962; MS109.002.031.00033 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, Venezuela, 1962; MS109.002.031.00034 (Box 31)
  - South American Expedition Notes, 1962; MS109.002.031.00035 (Box 31)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1955 -- 1975; MS109.002.031.00036 (Box 31)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1974; MS109.002.031.00037 (Box 31)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1974; MS109.002.031.00038 (Box 31)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1973 -- 1974; MS109.002.031.00039 (Box 31)
  - NY Evening Post, 1930 -- 1931; MS109.002.032.00001 (Box 32)
    Volume 1 of the diaries. Bound collection of article written while Crowe was assistant financial editor of the New York Evening Post.
  - Indo-China Diary, 1935 -- 1936; MS109.002.032.00002 (Box 32)
    Volume 2 of the diaries.
  - War Memoires, 1942 -- 1945; MS109.002.032.00003 (Box 32)
    Volume 3 of the diaries.
  - China Diary, 1948 -- 1949; MS109.002.032.00004 (Box 32)
    Volume 4 of the diaries.
  - Ceylon Diary, 1953; MS109.002.032.00005 (Box 32)
    Volume 5 of the diaries.
  - Ceylon Diary, 1954; MS109.002.032.00006 (Box 32)
    Volume 6 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further infromation.
  - Ceylon Diary, 1955; MS109.002.032.00007 (Box 32)
    Volume 7 of the diaries.
  - Ceylon Diary, 1956; MS109.002.032.00008 (Box 32)
    Volume 8 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further infromation.
  - US Diary, 1956 -- 1957; MS109.002.032.00009 (Box 32)
    Volume 9 of the diaries.
  - European Diary, 1957; MS109.002.032.00010 (Box 32)
    Volume 10 of the diaries.
  - Russian Diary, 1957; MS109.002.032.00011 (Box 32)
    Volume 11 of the diaries.
  - Sport and Travel East of Suez, 1957; MS109.002.032.00012 (Box 32)
    Volume 12 of the diaries.
  - State Department Diary, vol. 1, 1957 -- 1958; MS109.002.032.00013 (Box 32)
    Volume 13 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further infromation.
  - State Department Diary, vol. 2, 1958 -- 1959; MS109.002.032.00014 (Box 32)
    Volume 14 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further infromation.
  - John Foster Dulles, 1957 -- 1959; MS109.002.033.00001 (Box 33)
    Volume 15 of the diaries. Crowe's personal recollections of Dulles
  - African Diary, 1959; MS109.002.033.00002 (Box 33)
    Volume 16 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - African Diary, 1960; MS109.002.033.00003 (Box 33)
    Volume 17 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - African Diary, 1961; MS109.002.033.00004 (Box 33)
    Volume 19 of the diaries.
  - USA-Europe Diary, 1961; MS109.002.033.00005 (Box 33)
    Volume 20 of the diaries.
  - Diary, 1962; MS109.002.033.00006 (Box 33)
    Volume 21 of the diaries.
  - Diary, 1963; MS109.002.033.00007 (Box 33)
    Volume 22 of the diaries.
  - Diary, 1964; MS109.002.033.00008 (Box 33)
    Volume 23 of the diaries.
  - Diary, 1965; MS109.002.033.00009 (Box 33)
    Volume 24 of the diaries.
  - Dulles Interview with Philip K. Crowe, 1966; MS109.002.033.00010 (Box 33)
    Volume 25 of the diaries.
  - Diary, 1966; MS109.002.033.00011 (Box 33)
    Volume 26 of the diaries.
  - Diary, 1967; MS109.002.034.00001 (Box 34)
    Volume 27 of the diaries.
  - Diary, 1968; MS109.002.034.00002 (Box 34)
    Volume 28 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Diary, 1969; MS109.002.034.00003 (Box 34)
    Volume 29 of the diaries.
  - Norwegian Diary, 1969; MS109.002.034.00004 (Box 34)
    Volume
    30
  - Diary, 1970; MS109.002.034.00005 (Box 34)
    Volume 31 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Norwegian Diary, vol. 1, 1971; MS109.002.034.00006 (Box 34)
    Volume 32 of the diaries.
  - Norwegian Diary, vol. 2, 1971; MS109.002.034.00007 (Box 34)
    Volume 33 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Norwegian Diary, vol. 1, 1972; MS109.002.034.00008 (Box 34)
    Volume 34 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Norwegian Diary, vol. 2, 1972; MS109.002.035.00001 (Box 35)
    Volume 35 of the diaries.
  - Norwegian Diary, 1973; MS109.002.035.00002 (Box 35)
    Volume 36 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Danish Diary, 1973; MS109.002.035.00003 (Box 35)
    Volume 38 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Danish Diary, 1973; MS109.002.035.00004 (Box 35)
    Volume 39 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Danish Diary, 1974-01 -- 1974-07; MS109.002.035.00005 (Box 35)
    Volume 40 of the diaries.
  - Danish Diary, 1974; MS109.002.035.00006 (Box 35)
    Volume 41 of the diaries.
  - Danish Diary, 1974-07-01 -- 1974-12-31; MS109.002.035.00007 (Box 35)
    Volume 42 of the diaries.
  - Danish Diary, 1975; MS109.002.035.00008 (Box 35)
    Volume 43 of the diaries. Deletions were made to this volume by the US State Department. Please refer to the State Department letter inside the front cover for further information.
  - Diary, 1975; MS109.002.035.00009 (Box 35)
    Volume 44 of the diaries.
  - African Expedition Notes, 1968; MS109.002.036.00001 (Box 36)
  - African Expedition Notes: Maps, 1968; MS109.002.036.00002 (Box 36)
  - African Expedition Notes, 1968; MS109.002.036.00003 (Box 36)
  - African Expedition Notes, 1968; MS109.002.036.00004 (Box 36)
  - African Expedition Notes, 1968; MS109.002.036.00005 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Africa General, MS109.002.036.00006 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Belgian Congo, MS109.002.036.00007 (Box 36)
  - South African Notes: Dahomey, MS109.002.036.00008 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Game, Shooting, and Fishing, MS109.002.036.00009 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Ghana, MS109.002.036.00010 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Guinea, MS109.002.036.00011 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Ivory Coast, MS109.002.036.00012 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Kenya, MS109.002.036.00013 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Nyasland, MS109.002.036.00014 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Portugese Africa, MS109.002.036.00015 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Preface, South Africa Report, MS109.002.036.00016 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Protectorates, MS109.002.036.00017 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Rhodesias, MS109.002.036.00018 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Ruanda Urundi, MS109.002.036.00019 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Southwest Africa, MS109.002.036.00020 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: South Africa, MS109.002.036.00021 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Summing Up, MS109.002.036.00022 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Tanganyika, MS109.002.036.00023 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Zanzibar, MS109.002.036.00024 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Uganda, MS109.002.036.00025 (Box 36)
  - South Africa Notes: Maps, MS109.002.036.00026 (Box 36)
  - South Africa and Ceylon Clippings, 1959 -- 1961; MS109.002.036.00027 (Box 36)
  - Newsletters: South Africa, 1956 -- 1961; MS109.002.036.00028 (Box 36)
  - Newsletters: South Africa, 1957 -- 1960; MS109.002.036.00029 (Box 36)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1957 -- 1959; MS109.002.036.00030 (Box 36)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1959 -- 1961; MS109.002.036.00031 (Box 36)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1961 -- 1967; MS109.002.036.00032 (Box 36)
  - Drafts of Letters, 1967 -- 1968; MS109.002.036.00033 (Box 36)
  - Drafts of Diaries, 1973; MS109.002.036.00034 (Box 36)
  - Drafts of Diaries, 1975; MS109.002.036.00035 (Box 36)
  - World Wildlife Mission to Asia, 1965; MS109.002.036.00036 (Box 36)
  - World Wildlife Mission to the Middle East, 1966; MS109.002.036.00037 (Box 36)
  - World Wildlife Mission to Central America and Mexico, 1967; MS109.002.036.00038 (Box 36)
  - Indian Newsletter, 1955 -- 1956; MS109.002.036.00039 (Box 36)
  - Indian Newsletter, 1955 -- 1956; MS109.002.036.00040 (Box 36)
  - Articles: Book Reviews, MS109.002.037.00001 (Box 37)
  - Articles: China, MS109.002.037.00002 (Box 37)
  - Articles: Indo-China, MS109.002.037.00003 (Box 37)
  - Articles: England, 1943; MS109.002.037.00004 (Box 37)
  - Articles: Hunting in USA, 1941 -- 1953; MS109.002.037.00005 (Box 37)
  - Articles: Hunting, 1946 -- 1947; MS109.002.037.00006 (Box 37)
  - Articles: India, 1952 -- 1953; MS109.002.037.00007 (Box 37)
  - Articles for Magazine, MS109.002.037.00008 (Box 37)
  - Manuscript Draft of Sport is Where You Find It, MS109.002.037.00009 (Box 37)
  - Newsletters: Europe, 1957; MS109.002.037.00010 (Box 37)
  - Newsletters: Europe, 1961; MS109.002.037.00011 (Box 37)
  - Newsletters: Russian Diary, 1957; MS109.002.037.00012 (Box 37)
  - Newsletters: Russian Diary, MS109.002.037.00013 (Box 37)
- Embassy, Government and Military Papers, 1930 -- 1976; 1941 -- 1975; MS109.003; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series includes materials collected during Crowe's tenure in the Foreign Service as well as a copy of Crowe's war record during World War II. Some of the information contained in the war record may be sensitive. The materials in this series date to between 1941 and 1975. The materials include embassy briefing books for Denmark, guest books from the American Embassies in Copenhagen, Denmark and Oslo, Norway, an entertainment file for the United States embassy in Copenhagen, Fact Papers from the Executive Branch Liaison Office of the Eisenhower administration, and papers relating to official visits to Thule Airbase, Greenland, and Ascension Island.
  One of the briefing books for Denmark includes information on the ambassadorial residence in Copenhagen and is accompanied by a photo album containing photographs of the residence's interior. This book also includes information on protocol and security. The other briefing book focuses on the embassy staff. The Fact Papers were newsletters circulated among presidential appointees to enable them to follow the evolution of administration policy. There are also three certificates of appointment as US ambassador to the Union of South Africa, Norway and Denmark. The appointment to the Union of South Africa dates to the Eisenhower administration, and the appointment to Norway and Denmark fall under the Nixon administration.
  - Military War Records: Promotions, 1930 -- 1960; MS109.003.038.00001 (Box 38)
  - Military War Records: Citations, 1943 -- 1947; MS109.003.038.00002 (Box 38)